Dylan Alexander

Passionate Developer with experience in effectively and efficiently creating full-stack applications using a multitude of different technologies. Creative thinker, eager to learn, and B.S. in Computer Science from Arcadia University. Member of Arcadia Men's Swim Team for all four years.

4316 Susquehanna Dr Schwenksville, PA, 19473 (267) - 481 - 3258 <u>Dyalexander@comcast.net</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Destro Machines LLC, (Remote) — Computer Science Intern

May 2022 - PRESENT

- Develop Software for high-end swim equipment
- React, .Net, Entity Framework, Postgres, Js/Ts, C#, & SQL used to create immersive data visualization applications

Skippack Swim Club, Skippack, PA— Swim Coach

June 2018 - PRESENT

• Develop children's love for swimming while guiding them towards excellence in the pool

Spring Valley YMCA, Royersford, PA—Lifeguard

October 2017 - June 2020

 Maintained level of safety on pool deck, acted on emergencies, and maintained certifications in CPR & First Aid

EDUCATION

Arcadia University, Glenside, PA— B.S. Computer Science

August 2020 - May 2024

- Current 3.12 Overall Gpa, Dean's List Student (Spring 2021)
- 2021, 2023 MAC Winter Sports Honor Roll
- Trained on Men's Swim Team while achieving excellence in the classroom

PROJECTS

Caring for Friends — Flutter application supported w/ AWS & Amplify

- Develop data visualization flutter phone app for non-profit organization
- Use Google Maps Api to apply the traveling salesman problem to find best fit route
- Utilized Flutter, Dart, & AWS (DynamoDb, Lambda, Api Gateway)

SKILLS

Javascript/Typescript, Python, C#, Dart, Java, SQL

React, Entity Framework, .Net, Flutter

Docker

Git

AWS (DynamoDb, Lambda, Api Gateway)

CLASSWORK

Cyber Security & Networking:
Operating Systems, Intro to
Network Security, Computer
Organization & Architecture,
Database Systems & Management

Programming: Problem Solving through Algorithms 1 & 2, Website Development, Data Structures, Design & Analysis of Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Introduction to Data Mining, Computer Ethics, Research Writing CS

CERTIFICATIONS

Cloud Architecture (AWS Academy) - December 2020, <u>Credly</u>

Completed 40 hours of lectures, hands-on labs, and project work to develop understanding of Cloud Architecture